// Creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "During this period, Jose Rizalâ€™s works such as Noli Me Tangere and El Filibusterismo were written to awaken the mind of our countrymen.",
    answer: "a. Spanish Period",
    options: [
      "a. Spanish Period",
      "b. American Period",
      "c. Pre-Spanish Period",
      "d. Period of Enlightenment"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The Philippines had literature such as legends, folk tales, folk songs, and the like.",
    answer: "c. Pre-Spanish Period",
    options: [
      "a. Spanish Period",
      "b. Japanese Period",
      "c. Pre-Spanish Period",
      "d. Period of Enlightenment"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In this period, religious books were written, such as Doctrina Cristiana and Urbana and Felisa, to support or contradict the Catholic Church.",
    answer: "a. Spanish Period",
    options: [
      "a. Spanish Period",
      "b. American Period",
      "c. 21st Century Period",
      "d. Period of Enlightenment"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Filipino writers went into all forms of literature like news, reporting, poetry, stories, plays, essays, and novels which clearly depicted their love of country and their longings for independence.",
    answer: "b. American Period",
    options: [
      "a. Edsa I Period",
      "b. American Period",
      "c. Pre-Spanish Period",
      "d. The 3rd Republic Period"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Filipino literature was given a break during this period for the Filipino literature was prohibited from using. Many wrote plays, poems, short stories, etc. Topics and themes were often about life in the provinces.",
    answer: "a. Japanese Period",
    options: [
      "a. Japanese Period",
      "b. American Period",
      "c. Pre-Spanish Period",
      "d. American Period"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Haiku and Tanaga were influenced by what period?",
    answer: "b. Japanese Period",
    options: [
      "a. Spanish Period",
      "b. Japanese Period",
      "c. 21st Century Period",
      "d. Period of Enlightenment"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "This period presented new trends in writing using modern technology.",
    answer: "b. 21st Century Period",
    options: [
      "a. Edsa I Period",
      "b. 21st Century Period",
      "c. Pre-Spanish Period",
      "d. The 3rd Republic Period"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "This literary period witnessed newspapers, which were once branded crony newspapers, become instant opposition papers.",
    answer: "d. Edsa I Period",
    options: [
      "a. Japanese Period",
      "b. American Period",
      "c. Pre-Spanish Period",
      "d. Edsa I Period"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Poetry during this period was romantic and revolutionary.",
    answer: "a. The 3rd Republic Period",
    options: [
      "a. The 3rd Republic Period",
      "b. Edsa I Period",
      "c. 21st Century Period",
      "d. Pre-Spanish Period"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Poetry during this period was dealt with patience, regard for native culture and customs.",
    answer: "d. New Society Period",
    options: [
      "a. The 3rd Republic Period",
      "b. 21st Century Period",
      "c. Edsa I Period",
      "d. New Society Period"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Philippine regional literature can be BEST described as ___________.",
    answer: "a. Dynamic",
    options: [
      "a. Dynamic",
      "b. Outdated",
      "c. Spoken",
      "d. Traditional"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Imagery in poetry pertains to _____________.",
    answer: "a. Mental pictures",
    options: [
      "a. Mental pictures",
      "b. Unique drawings",
      "c. Vague resemblances",
      "d. Word creations"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The use of the vernacular in regional literature is ___________",
    answer: "b. encouraged so that the culture and tradition of a people are upheld despite effects of modernity",
    options: [
      "a. discouraged because many people do not understand a piece not written in either English or Tagalog",
      "b. encouraged so that the culture and tradition of a people are upheld despite effects of modernity",
      "c. opposed for the reason that it constraints the expression of thoughts, feelings, and ideas of a writer",
      "d. affirmed by many for it allows free flow of feelings and insights not understandable to readers"
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "A valid observation of literary development in the Philippines is that _______.",
    answer: "d. Literature developed alongside Philippine history.",
    options: [
      "a. History is recorded only in the oral tradition of the country.",
      "b. No literature could reflect the richness of our country's experiences.",
      "c. Literary masterpieces are written by great persons with great remembrances.",
      "d. Literature developed alongside Philippine history."
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Because of the archipelagic nature of the Philippines, its geographical features, and the presence of various ethno-linguistic groups in the country, regional literature has become ____________.",
    answer: "c. rich and varied",
    options: [
      "a. anti-modern and traditional",
      "b. short yet vivid",
      "c. rich and varied",
      "d. nationalistic"
    ],
  },
];
